<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<metadata xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:title>Exercise 1 - Data Stewardship (2020S)</dc:title>
    <dc:creator>Matthias Weiß</dc:creator>
    <dc:subject>Finding patterns in the internet's highest rated movies</dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
        IMDB (https://www.imdb.com/) is a popular platform for people to discover new movies and tv shows, as well as to rate ones
        they have already seen. They list the highest rated movies on the Top 250 page (https://www.imdb.com/chart/top), which thus
        is an easy way to explore movies that a lot of people really liked. What we are trying to do in this experiment is to find
        patterns in these 250 movies, we would not go as far as call it "recipes" for popular movies, but that is sort of what we
        are trying to find. While we are pretty sure that such recipes do not exist, otherwise Hollywood filmmakers would have
        probably found them by now, we do think that there is useful information hiding in this particular list. Concrete
        questions we are trying to answer are: are there actresses*actors that frequently appear in high rated movies?
        Are certain genres more popular than others? Does a certain timeframe have a higher density of highly rated
        movies? It is noteworthy that we took the data from a publicly accessible dataset
        (https://www.kaggle.com/bartius/imdb-top-250-movies-info/data) created by Nigel Cox (https://www.kaggle.com/bartius)
         on January 5th, 2019. While we could have scraped the data ourself, we instead checked it against the current Top
         250 list and came to the conclusion that the list stayed almost identical, thus we did not see the need to collect
         the data once again (also the assignment states that we have to use data from an external source).
    </dc:description>
    <dc:date>01.04.2020</dc:date>
    <dc:identifier>https://zenodo.org/badge/latestdoi/251582525</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>English</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Free access</dc:rights>
</metadata>
